<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Magnus Petersen </title>
    <link>https://magnuspetersen.github.io/portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Magnus Petersen </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://magnuspetersen.github.io/portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ESG Company Score Evaluation </title>
      <link>https://magnuspetersen.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magnuspetersen.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>This is my attempt of estimating ESG scores, a scoring system for evaluating environment, social and governance impact of an entity. The scoring is done using a zero shot multi label categorization using a pretrained S-BERT Model. The model uses keywords corresponding to E, S and G in order to categorize articles as belonging to the three categories. If the article is classified as belonging to one or more of the categories it is assigned a score based on the relative positivity of the article, which is in turn calculated by comparing the score of the label &amp;ldquo;negative&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;positive&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Conformal Autoencoder</title>
      <link>https://magnuspetersen.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magnuspetersen.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>This is an implementation of the LOca, local conformal autoencoder, model as described in the PNAS Paper &amp;ldquo;Local conformal autoencoder for standardized data coordinates&amp;rdquo; by Erez Peterfreund et al. [1] More specifically it is the implementation of their toy model in the section 6.2/6.3 as it highlights the abilities and the use cases of the model well.
I have no affiliation with the authors, I just liked the paper and wanted to share my implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of Action Prediction</title>
      <link>https://magnuspetersen.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magnuspetersen.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>My Kaggle challenge notebooks for the &amp;ldquo;Mechanism of Action&amp;rdquo; contest. All my iterations and insights. This was my first Kaggle challenge, as such it is not fully optimized, as I wanted to get a feel for the competitions first.
Challenge Outline The goal of the challenge is to use 100 cell viability features and 772 gene expression features to find the corresponding 206 target mechanisms. The features are the results from the L1000 and Prism assay respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
